Senior.
师兄
my reward!
奖励
You said
你说过的
I would be rewarded if I passed the assessment.
我考核通过有奖励
I want to embrace you.
我要抱抱
You... What's wrong with you?
你 你怎么了
I'm fine.
我没事
Let me help you come back.
我先扶你回去吧
OK.
好
Take care.
小心
Why are you so cold?
怎么冷成这样
Master.
师父
Yixin.
一昕
Don't hold on with your internal force.
莫要用内力强撑
Senior.
师兄
The cold air invaded him.
寒气入侵
His veins are cold,
经脉冰寒
causing poor blood flow.
血流不畅
It's my fault.
都怪我
He became so because I interrupted him while he was practicing martial arts.
是我打断他练武才这样的
Hurry up to take coals.
速去取炭火
Yes. Master.
是 师父
Come.
来
The medicine given by Crown Prince may be useful.
太子送的丹药或许管用
You finally look better.
终于好些了
Yixin,
一昕
is there still anything wrong with you?
你可还有不适
I feel better.
徒儿好多了
Thank you, Master.
多谢师父
Master,
师父
you used much magic power just now.
你刚刚耗费了诸多灵力
You need rest.
需要休养
I will take care of my senior.
师兄这儿就由我来照顾
Set your heart at rest.
放心吧
OK.
好
This is the medicine Crown Prince gave to me.
这是太子给我的丹药
He said it could strengthen the body.
说是能够固本培元
Taking it may be helpful to you.
你服下它或许会有帮助
No, thanks.
不用了
I... I won't take it.
我 我不吃
Why?
为什么
Mingyang gave it to you.
这是铭炀给你的
If I take it,
如果我服了
you will let him down.
你就辜负他心意了
But he gave me the medicine
可是他送我这丹药
originally for emergency response.
本来就是应急用的
Now it's an emergency.
现在就是紧急情况
Anyway, I won't take it.
反正我不吃
You.
你
Since you won't take it,
你既然不吃
it's useless for me to keep it.
我留着也没用
It would be better to throw it away.
不如扔了算了
You do so just because it's useless.
无用就要扔了
If I'm of no use in the future,
那我以后无用了
will you also throw me away?
是不是也要把我扔了
You are a person, not a thing.
你是人 又不是东西
How can I throw you away easily?
哪能说扔就扔啊
I know.
我知道了
It's not that you don't want to see the medicine.
你根本不是不想看见这颗丹药
You just don't want to see me.
你是不想看见我
So cold.
好冷
You still feel cold?
你还冷啊
The fire is not hot enough. Let me take more coals.
火不够了 我去加点炭
No. No. No.
不 不 不
If there is a warm embrace now,
现在如果有一个温暖的抱抱
that will be the best.
那比什么都好
No.
算了吧
You don't want your reward?
你的奖励不要了
You're uncomfortable now.
你现在身体不舒服
Make it another day.
改天吧
Can you get your hands off me?
你能不能先把我的手放开啊
Your hands are so warm.
你的手好暖啊
Why are you blushing?
你脸怎么这么红啊
Is it very hot here?
这儿很热吗
Nangong Yixin,
南宫一昕
you fooled me again.
你又耍我
I heard someone was ill
我可是听说某个人病倒了
and came here in a hurry.
我这急急忙忙赶过来
It looks like you're fine.
看着也没怎么样
You still have the time
还有这闲工夫
to tease the beauty.
逗佳人呢
Stop.
别闹行不行
If Master didn't come quickly,
刚刚如果不是师父来得快
I would have been the iceman.
那我就真成冰冻人了 我
Is it possible that you were poisoned?
莫非是中毒
After Your Highness returned from Manghuang forest,
殿下从莽荒森林回来后
you are always gloomy.
一直愁眉不展
What are you worried about?
可有什么烦恼
Lingyu,
凌宇
do you know how to
你知道要怎么样
make a girl happy?
才能讨女孩儿的欢心吗
Gifts.
送礼物吧
Girls
女孩子
may all like surprising gifts.
应该都会喜欢惊喜的礼物
Surprising gifts.
惊喜礼物
Surprise.
惊喜
What may Qingqing like?
卿卿可能会喜欢什么
Your Highness is preparing gifts for Lady Qingqing.
殿下是在为路二小姐准备礼物
Since I can't go to accompany Qingqing personally,
既然本王不能亲自去陪伴卿卿
I will send
那便送一些
some things she may like there.
她可能会喜欢的东西过去
Thus,
如此
in the day-to-day
她便能在日复一日的
boring practice,
乏味练习当中
she can live more happily and comfortably.
过得愉悦和舒适一些
Your Highness is considerate.
殿下有心了
Be quick, help me think
快帮本王想想
what else she may like.
还有什么是她可能会喜欢的
Yes, Your Highness.
是 殿下
I have never seen
我从来没有看见过
so many blooming cherry blossoms.
这么多盛开的樱花
These cherry blossoms are in full bloom.
这些樱花开得奢靡
If only they will never fade.
要是能永开不败就好了
You must know
你应该明白的
your illness is related to Qingqing.
你的病是因为卿儿
Maybe God is kidding.
也许是天意弄人
But there is actually a trade-off
但你跟卿儿的灵力
between your magic power and Qingqing's.
就是此消彼长的
But why?
可这是为什么
In Qiyuan continent,
启元大陆
there is no precedent.
从来没有这样的先例
I don't know the reason either,
虽然为师也不知道原因
but you will die
但再这么继续下去
if it continues.
你会没命的
Yixin,
一昕
you are seriously ill,
你重病在身
and everything is about her
皆因她而起
For the sake of your health,
为了你的身体
you should keep a distance from her.
还是保持距离得好啊
Master, you are here as well.
师父也在
Master.
师父
Think it over.
你好好思量
What did you talk about?
你们刚刚在说什么
Master is so serious.
师父那么严肃
Nothing. Nothing.
没什么 没什么
What is hidden behind you?
你这背后藏着什么东西
Nothing.
没什么
You. You let me go.
你 你给我解开
You.
你这是
I sent you cherry blossoms
赠人樱花
and you also reward me with cherry blossoms.
报以樱花
I.
我
I'm afraid that you're bored
我就是怕你一个人
while recuperating alone in the room.
在屋子里养病憋闷得慌
I picked a branch of flowers to relieve your boredom.
摘一枝花给你解解闷
Such beautiful cherry blossoms
这么美的樱花
match me, a man with an imposing appearance
配我这样气宇轩昂
and casual and elegant bearing style.
风流倜傥的人
Good.
很好
You have great taste.
品位不错嘛
My Lady, you are finally enlightened.
小姐终于想通了
You should have more contact with Crown Prince
您多和太子接触
and send him more elaborate gifts.
多送他一些精心准备的礼物
Even if his heart is made of stone,
就算他的心是石头做的
he should be moved by you.
也该被您感动了
Zhenzhu,
珍珠
don't talk too much in the palace.
宫中不要多言
Yes, My Lady.
是 小姐
Red bean pastry.
红豆酥
Your Highness,
殿下
Lady Yunxi came.
路大小姐来了
Just in time,
正好
since you came,
既然你来了
can you do me a favor?
可否帮本王一个忙
You are welcome.
殿下客气
As long as I can make it,
只要是云溪能帮忙的
I must try my best.
自当尽心
According to my own thoughts,
本王按照自己的想法
I prepare these gifts for Qingqing,
为卿儿准备了这些
but I don't know whether she will like them.
只是不知道她到底喜不喜欢
You are her elder sister.
你是她姐姐
You must know her better than me.
肯定比本王更了解她
Quickly help me take a look.
你快帮本王看看
Yes. Your Highness.
是 殿下
You all get out.
你们先退下吧
Yes. Yes.
是 是
If there is something she doesn't like,
若是有她不喜欢的
you should tell me in time.
一定要及时告知本王
Even though she is screwing with Lord Jin
就算她在莽荒森林
in Manghuang forest,
与晋王纠缠不清
Crown Prince still cares about her.
太子也还是放不下她吗
Qingqing,
卿儿
what actually did you do
你到底做了什么
to make Crown Prince have such a deep affection for you?
让太子对你这般情深意重
You're awake.
你醒了
Do you feel better?
身体可有好些
I'm fine.
我没事啊
It's stuffy in the room.
屋里闷死了
I came out for some air.
出来透透气嘛
As long as you're fine.
没事就好
Are you
怎么
practicing the art of illusion?
练幻形术呢
I want to disappear the trees in the mountains
我想把这山间的树木幻化消失
but I failed over and over again.
但总是不成功
It is simple.
这有何难
You want to learn that?
想学啊
Let me teach you.
我教你啊
Follow me.
跟我学啊
Your feet should be like solid rocks.
脚如磐石
Take a deep breath into your belly
气沉丹田
and gather your ideas in your hands.
将意念聚于掌中
What you think is what you see.
所想即所见
I did it!
成功了
Lord Jin.
晋王殿下
Lady Qingqing.
路二小姐
Lingyu, why are you here?
凌宇 你怎么来了
Crown Prince is afraid that Lady Qingqing
这是太子殿下担心二小姐
lives an inconvenient life in Youhuang.
在幽簧里生活不便
There are the gifts he specially prepared for you.
特地为您准备的礼物
They are all your favorite things.
都是您喜欢的东西
Please accept them, Lady Qingqing.
请二小姐收下
Here is the letter from Crown Prince.
这儿还有一封太子殿下的信
Please open it personally, Lady Qingqing.
请路二小姐亲启
Since I'm busy with the official business,
因公务缠身
I can't go to Youhuang to accompany you.
无法到幽簧里相伴
I prepared what you need.
遂备上所需之物
I hope you will like them.
望卿欢喜
These are all that Crown Prince prepared for me?
这些都是太子殿下给我准备的
Too many.
也太多了吧
Lingyu,
凌宇
after you come back, help me express my gratitude to Crown Prince.
你回去帮我好好谢谢太子殿下
As long as you like them.
您喜欢就好
Wait. Wait.
等 等一下
While we are practicing magic power,
修炼灵力呢
the most important thing is to purify the heart and diminish the passion.
最重要的是清心寡欲
Mingyang sends both food and playthings.
铭炀又送吃的又送玩的
They will distract your attention.
这确实会影响你的注意力
Lingyu,
凌宇
take them back.
赶紧带回去啊
This...
这
Your Highness,
晋王殿下
I was ordered
属下奉命
to send these things here.
一定要将东西送到
I don't dare to take them back without permission.
不敢擅自拿回
Since I have completed my task,
既然任务已经完成
I'm going to leave.
属下先告退了
Diabolo.
空竹
You are so happy.
这么高兴呢
Ginseng.
野参
Senior,
师兄
you have just recovered from a severe illness.
你大病初愈
There are many tonics.
我看这里面有很多补品
They can strengthen your body.
正好可以帮你补补身子
She cares about me very much.
她还是很关心我的
Senior.
师兄
Don't worry.
你也别太担心了
Master Rongyun is here.
有容云大师在
Everything will be better.
一切啊 都会好起来的
Sister Qingqing,
卿儿妹妹
how did your hand become so?
你这手是怎么弄的
I accidentally cut it just now.
刚才不小心划到了
Hurry up to put a bandage on it.
你快去包扎一下
Don't stay here.
别在这儿了
Hurry up. I'm ok.
快去快去 没事
I want to wait until they come out,
我还是先等师父他们出来
and then treat my wound.
再说吧
Qingqing,
卿卿
he often makes you angry
他平日里总是惹你生气
but you still care about him so much.
你还这么关心他
His bark
他这个人吧
is worse than his bite.
嘴毒心热
I know him.
我懂他
But I'm really worried about him.
可我真的好担心他呀
I can't even breathe.
担心得都有点喘不上气了
Master and he have been in the room for long.
师父和他都进去这么久了
Why haven't they come out yet?
怎么还不出来啊
Isn't there actually something wrong, is there?
不会真有什么事吧
I haven't been so anxious, even when I'm ill.
我自己生病都没有这么担心过
Do you know that?
你知道吗
Wan Qing once had a fever,
有一次菀青发热
ad I was as nervous as you are.
我也像你一样
I even didn't dare to sit down.
紧张得都不敢坐下
Do you know why?
你知道这是为什么吗
Because...
因为
Because I like her.
因为我喜欢她
Like?
喜欢
Yes.
对啊
Think it over on your own.
你自己好好想想吧
Master.
师父
♫It tugs at my heartstrings♫
你醒了
Slow down.
慢点
Where is Qingqing?
卿卿呢
She didn't find anything, did she?
卿卿没发现什么吧
♫I can see it from your face♫
为师让她出去了
You got ill twice in a row,
你接连两次病症发作
which consumed your magic power quickly.
体内的灵力消耗迅疾
Don't approach Qingqing anymore.
莫要再与卿卿接近了
From today on, you wear this
从今日起你便戴上此物
and keep a distance from Qinqing.
与卿儿保持距离吧
Master.
师父
The distance bracelet
这距离手环
is unnecessary.
不必如此吧
If you don't wear it,
你若是不戴
I will tell Qingqing the truth.
为师便把实情告诉卿儿
No.
不要
No. Master.
不要 师父
Don't tell Qingqing the truth.
您千万别告诉卿儿
♫My missing turns into frost and snow. It's hard to end it♫
我不想让她多想
Disciple,
徒儿
as long as you obey my words.
听话便是
Master,
师父
how about him?
他怎么样了
Let me take a look.
我去看看他
Qingqing,
卿儿
follow me.
随为师来
How about my senior?
师兄他到底怎么样了
What kind of illness did he have?
他到底生的是何病啊
♫Who is still missing it♫
不用担心
He's awake.
他已经醒来了
But his body still needs rest.
只是身体仍需休养
He needs to be on a retreat for some time.
需要闭关静养一段时间
These days,
这些时日
♫They fade away♫
你勿要再去叨扰他了
Let him quietly take a rest.
让他好生静养
But how can he be alone?
可是他一个人怎么能行
Let me look after him.
还是让我去照顾他吧
Stop talking more.
无须多言
This is what Yixin means.
这是一昕的意思
Qingqing.
卿儿
♫If your warmth can melt frost and snow♫
你可明白
what he means?
他的意思
Why is he unwilling to see me?
他为何不愿意见我
Master.
师父
This is...
这是
This is the distance bracelet.
这是距离手环
You and Yixin each wear one.
你和一昕各戴一只
While you are practicing,
在你修炼的期间
you two
你们两人
should keep a distance of three feet.
需保持三尺远的距离
Once the distance is shorter than three feet,
一旦少于该距离
the bracelet will tighten,
手环便会收紧
♫My missing turns into frost and snow. It's hard to end it♫
疼痛难忍
Wearing the bracelet
戴上此手环
can urge you to practice better and harder.
可以促使你更好地勤加修炼
Master.
师父
♫Only hope you can't see my pains♫
若是卿儿好好修炼
will the bracelet...
那这个手环是不是就
Thus, I can't approach him.
这下不能靠近他了
I saw Nangong just now.
我刚刚看过南宫了
He's better.
他好多了
Don't worry.
你就别担心了
Be happy.
开心点
How about taking you to eat something delicious?
要不我带你去吃好吃的
No. I have no appetite.
不想吃 没胃口
You have no appetite?
没胃口
It's the first time that I've heard
我还是第一次听你说
you say you have no appetite.
你没胃口呢
It seems that our Senior Nangong
看来我们这南宫兄
is really charming.
魅力是挺大的
Sikong,
司空
today you said you were worried about Sister Wan Qing
你今天说你紧张菀青姐
because you like her.
是因为喜欢她
I'm worried about my senior.
那我紧张师兄
Is it because I like him?
难道也是因为喜欢他
You shouldn't ask me.
这个你可不能问我
You have to ask your heart.
你得问自己的心
I seem to really like him,
我好像确实是喜欢他
but I also like Baihe,
可是我也喜欢百合
like Sister Wan Qing and Xiaoyi.
喜欢菀青姐 小乙
What's the difference?
这有什么不一样啊
This... This is certainly different.
这 这当然不一样了
One is the affection between men and women
这一个是男女之间的喜欢
and another is the affection between friends.
一个是朋友之间的喜欢
The affection between friends
这个朋友之间的喜欢呢
is very simple.
很简单
While you are getting along with him,
就是你和他相处起来啊
you feel very comfortable and free.
很舒服 很自在
But the affection between men and women
而这男女之间的喜欢吧
is both simple and complex.
既简单又复杂
When it is simple,
简单的时候呢
you just want to
你就是想开开心心地
be with him happily.
跟他在一起
When it is complex,
而复杂的时候
your mood can be affected by his.
你的情绪会被他的情绪影响
You will feel happy because of his happiness
你会因为他的开心而开心
and feel sad because of his sadness.
难过而难过
You always want to protect him
你总是想要保护他
and accompany him.
想陪着他
Because I can't let you celebrate your birthday alone.
因为我不能让你一个人过生辰
It turns out that my feeling for Nangong Yixin
原来我对南宫一昕
is this kind of affection.
是这种喜欢
Mr. Lu,
路大人
tell me about Lu Qingqing's origin.
你跟本宫讲讲路卿卿的身世
Why are Your Majesty suddenly interested in
王后怎么突然对小女的身世
my daughter's origin?
感兴趣了
I just feel curious.
本宫只是觉得奇怪
When Mr. Lu
当年路大人
brought Lu Qingqing back,
将路卿卿带回来之时
you said she was the daughter you left in No Magic Valley.
说她是你遗留在废灵谷的女儿
But when selecting concubines,
可选妃之时
I checked her birth.
本宫查过她的生辰
She was born in July, Qiyuan 552,
她是启元五百五十二年七月
but you went to No Magic Valley for the first time
而路大人第一次到废灵谷
in September, Qiyuan 552.
是五百五十二年九月
You first led the army
你头一次率兵
to find the magic girl and the magic power stone
去找灵女和灵力石
but failed.
寻找未果
However, you brought Lu Qingqing back.
却将路卿卿带回来
Therefore,
如此推断
Lu Qingqing
路大人跟路卿卿
is not the biological daughter of Mr. Lu.
并非亲生父女
Your Majesty, you are right.
王后说得没错
Lu Qingqing
路卿卿
is the daughter of the magic girl and Li An Guild Leader.
其实是灵女与利安门主的女儿
Mr. Lu, how dare you!
路大人 你大胆
The magic girl escaped with the magic power stone.
灵女携灵力石出逃
Her crime is unforgivable.
罪无可恕
You even dare to hide her daughter,
你竟敢私藏她的女儿
and conceal her identity.
还隐瞒她的身份
Is it that since you have been Prince Regent for a long time,
莫不是你摄政王当久了
you view yourself as the real king?
就把自己当真正的王了
Please figure it out, Your Majesty.
王后明鉴
I've worked hard to assist Crown Prince for many years
老臣尽心辅佐太子多年
and I've never had the idea of arrogation.
绝无僭越之心
In that year, I failed to find the magic power stone,
当年寻灵力石未果
and it makes me always feel ashamed and uneasy.
心中一直愧疚难安
I brought her daughter back
我把她的血脉带回来
because I want to use her
也是想着能够用她
to attract the magic girl
把灵女引出来
and then take the magic power stone back.
拿回灵力石
I didn't expect that the magic girl had died.
可不曾想灵女已经死了
What?
什么
The magic girl died?
灵女死了
My trusted follower
属下亲信在废灵谷
found the magic girl's corpse in No Magic Valley.
寻到了灵女的尸首
He confirmed it was her.
确认是她
OK.
行了
Get up.
起来吧
Thank you, My Majesty.
谢王后
How about the magic power stone?
那灵力石呢
He carefully searched the place around the corpse
他仔细翻查了尸首附近
but didn't find the magic power stone.
并未发现灵力石的踪影
So our so many years of efforts
那我们这么多年的努力
were in vain.
就白费了
For twenty years.
二十年了
there has been no trace of the magic power stone.
灵力石没有踪影
Mr. Lu,
路大人
why should I still employ you?
本宫还要你何用
Calm down, My Majesty.
王后息怒
We actually gained something.
其实也并不是一无所获
Though the clue about the magic girl can't be followed up,
灵女这条线虽然断了
we still have Lu Qingqing.
但我们手里还有路卿卿
Lu Qingqing.
路卿卿
Do you mean
你的意思是说
Lu Qingqing is related to the magic power stone?
路卿卿和灵力石有关
Didn't you investigate it before?
之前你不是探查过了嘛
Lu Qingqing didn't hide the magic power stone.
路卿卿并未私藏灵力石吗
So I have an audacious guess
所以老臣有一个大胆的猜想
that the magic power stone
也许灵力石
may be hidden in the body of Lu Qingqing.
就藏在路卿卿的体内
The magic power of the stone is strong.
灵力石灵力强大
Who has the ability
谁有这个能力
to seal it in a person's body?
将它封印在人的身体里
Normal people perhaps can't do that.
常人或许不能
But how about the magic girl?
但灵女呢
The generations of the magic girl protect the stone.
灵女一脉代代守护着灵力石
It's because the magic pneuma in their blood vessels
就是因为她们血脉中的
matches the magic power stone.
灵气与灵力石契合
How to prove your guess?
怎么才能证明你的猜测呢
The magic power of the stone is strong.
灵力石灵力强大
Though it is sealed in a person's body,
封印在人的体内
there must be a material object.
一定会有化形之物
Therefore, I will ask someone to confirm that.
所以老臣会再派人前去确认
This is the last opportunity for you.
那本宫就再给你最后一次机会
If there is still no trace of the magic power stone,
如果灵力石还是没有踪影
you won't need to be Prince Regent anymore.
你这个官也就不用再做了
Yes. Your Majesty.
是 王后
Without me,
没有我
how can she and Crown Prince have today's position?
怎么会有她跟太子的位置
Now she asks me for the magic power stone.
现在跟我要灵力石
Qi Yi,
齐翼
where do you think Lu Qingqing can
你觉得路卿卿会把灵力石
hide the magic power stone?
藏在哪儿
I don't know.
属下不知
But since I found nothing after search in that day,
可自从那日查探未果
I always think of
属下时常回想
a detail on that occasion.
当时的情景有一个细节
I don't know whether it is related to this matter.
不知是否与其有关
That red dot seemed to be shining.
那个红点似乎还在发光
The shining red dot?
会发光的红点
Is it the magic power stone?
难道那就是灵力石
Go to find Lu Qingqing at once
你马上去找路卿卿
to figure it out.
把这件事确认清楚
Yes, Your Grace.
是 大人
I haven't seen the senior for two days.
这两天都没有见到师兄了
I don't know whether he has recovered.
也不知道他好了没有
Qingqing,
卿儿
a confused state of mind
思绪纷乱
is a great taboo in practice.
是修行的大忌
You feel ill at ease.
你此刻思绪不宁
What's wrong?
怎么回事
Sorry, Master.
对不起 师父
You must eliminate distracting thoughts
务必排除杂念
and focus on your ideas themselves.
专注于意念本身
If you can't do that,
倘若连这点都做不到
how can you control the magic power?
怎么掌控灵力
Yes.
是
Master.
师父
Flying with a sword
御剑飞行
is the compulsory skill of warlocks.
是灵力者的必修之术
Today let me see
今日便让为师来看看
how well you master it.
你掌握到什么程度了
Yes, Master.
是 师父
Senior.
师兄
You've recovered?
你好了
I have words to tell you.
我有话对你说
Concentrate on your practice.
修炼专心点
Senior.
师兄
I have words... Qingqing.
我有话 卿儿
Who are you?
你是谁
Are you alright?
你没事吧
All right.
没事
Am I so heavy
是不是我太沉了
that I pressed you?
压到你了
I'm fine.
无妨
You are in poor health and still come to protect me.
你身体不好还要来保护我
So why don't you go away now.
那你还不快分开
Don't you feel pain when the bracelet stabs you?
这手环刺你不痛吗
I don't want to separate from you even though I feel pain.
痛我也不要分开
I... I forgot you also would feel pain.
我 我忘了你也会疼
Are you OK?
你没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
Master.
师父
Qingqing.
卿儿
Why do you still stay here?
你怎么还在这里
Did you stay up all night?
你是一宿没睡吗
Master,
师父
I want to know
我想知道师兄
how the senior is now.
现在到底怎么样了
When his magic power is not stable,
他在灵力未稳的情况下
he consumed much magic power.
透支了大量灵力
His illness is very serious.
病发得甚为厉害
I have regulated his breath for a whole night.
为师已为他调息了一晚
Now he is much better.
现在已经好多了
Master,
师父
I want to take a look at him.
我想去看他一眼
Just a look.
一眼就好
Qingqing,
卿儿
Sikong and I will look after him well.
我与司空会照顾好他
Set your heart at ease.
你放心
Your Grace,
大人
I sneaked into Lady Qingqing's room yesterday,
属下昨日潜入二小姐卧房
and used the magic power
使用灵力
to pick the red dot in her ear.
摘取二小姐耳边的红色光点
But my magic power was sucked away.
不想灵力却被吸走
Around Lady Qingqing,
二小姐身边
suddenly a barrier like a lotus formed
突然升起了莲花状的结界
to protect her.
保护她
So I failed.
所以失败了
Your magic power was sucked away?
灵力被吸走
And a barrier like a lotus formed?
还升起莲花状的结界
Did Qingqing make it?
是二小姐自己升起来的吗
No.
不是
Lady Qingqing was asleep then.
二小姐当时还在熟睡中
It was the sound of my collision with the magic power
是属下被灵力弹开
that awakened Lady Qingqing.
发出的声响惊醒了二小姐
Sucking the magic power and forming a barrier?
吸走灵力还升起结界
Besides,
还有
when I fought with Lady Qingqing yesterday,
昨夜与二小姐交手时
I found
属下发现
she made fast progress in the magic power.
二小姐的灵力进步神速
If she continues to practice for a time,
若再修炼一段时间
I'm afraid my magic power
属下的灵力
will be inferior to Lady Qingqing's.
恐怕要在二小姐之下了
In just one month,
这短短一个月的时间
she made such fast progress.
进步这么神速
Even Nangong Yixin
这就是当年的南宫一昕
couldn't do that in the past.
也做不到啊
My Lady and I saw with our own eyes
我与小姐亲眼看到二小姐
that when Lady Qingqing was in danger,
她在遭遇危难之时
she showed a strong barrier.
爆发出了强大结界
And the barrier was like a lotus water base.
且结界是莲花水座模样
It seems that the magic girl really
看来灵女是真的把灵力石
sealed the magic power stone in Qingqing's body.
封印在卿卿体内了
If it's true,
如果是这样的话
we can't take it with force.
那不能强取了
We have to find another solution.
我们得另外想办法
Do Your Grace doubt
大人怀疑
there is something wrong with the treasure?
宝物有问题
The fusang fruit is false.
这扶桑果是假的
How can it be?
这怎么可能
Your Grace,
大人
I really took it
属下确实是从二小姐的手中
from Lady Qingqing.
拿来的
Qingqing intends to
卿卿这点小心眼啊
mix the false with the genuine.
想以假乱真
Good.
也好
Let's turn her trick to our own use.
我们就将计就计
Your Majesty,
王后
Lord Lu asks to see you.
路大人求见
Please, Your Grace.
路大人请
Pay respects to Your Majesty.
王后娘娘金安
As you were.
免礼
You all get out.
你们都退下吧
Mr. Lu,
路大人
do you bring some good news?
这是带来什么好消息了
Do you know the information about the magic power stone?
可否有了灵力石的下落
Exactly.
的确
I asked Qi Yi to confirm that.
老臣让齐翼确认过了
The magic power stone is actually in Qingqing's body.
灵力石的确就在路卿卿的体内
Since you have found it,
既然找到了
why don't take it here quickly?
为何还不赶紧取来
Isn't it that Mr. Lu
莫不是路大人
can't defeat even a girl?
连个小丫头都打不过吧
Your majesty,
王后
I have tried to take it with force,
老臣已经尝试过强取
but the magic power stone has a barrier.
但是灵力石自带反噬结界
It can't be taken with force.
强取不成
But I have found another solution.
不过老臣又想出了另一个办法
What?
什么办法
It's said that the magic power stone
相传灵力石
was made of the blood and magic pneuma
是启元大陆开辟之初
of the first magic girl and the first Emperor
由初代灵女和初任王上的血
when Qiyuan continent was initially explored.
与灵气凝聚而成
Afterwards, it is guarded by the generations of the magic girl.
之后由灵女一脉代代守护
I think
那么老臣想
if the royal lineage combines with the magical girl's lineage,
如果让王血和灵女血脉结合
perhaps we can take the magic power stone out.
说不定可以取出灵力石
You mean
你的意思是
let Lu Qingqing marry Crown Prince?
让路卿卿与太子成婚
It's impossible.
不可能
She is the daughter of a sinner.
她是罪人之女
And she is naughty
且生性顽劣
and doesn't obey rules.
毫无规矩
I can't let her become Crown Princess
我不可能让她当太子妃
to harm Mingyang.
去祸害铭炀
Besides,
况且
I have deposed her as Crown Princess.
她又被我废除了太子妃之位
If I proclaim her Crown Princess again,
若是再立她当太子妃
won't I embarrass myself?
岂不是打自己的脸
It's impossible.
不可能
Absolutely impossible.
绝对不可能
Calm down, Your Majesty.
王后稍安勿躁
Listen to my analysis.
听老臣细细分析
Now for Qiyuan continent
如今对于启元大陆
and Nangong royalty,
和南宫王室来说
the only important thing
只有一样东西最重要
is the magic power stone.
那就是灵力石
Only when Crown Prince gets the magic power stone,
太子也只有拿到了灵力石
can he successfully ascend to the throne.
才能顺利地继位登基
Recently Lord Jin gets close to Lu Qinqing.
最近晋王与路卿卿走得很近
If he forestalls Crown Prince,
如果让晋王抢了先
I'm afraid Crown Prince's throne
那太子这王位
will not be guaranteed.
恐怕就真的不保了
You mean
你的意思是
let Crown Prince have sex with Lu Qingqing secretly?
让太子和路卿卿私下圆房
But if it gets out,
但要是传出去
the fame of Crown Prince will...
那太子的名声
Be relieved, Your Majesty.
王后放心
Even if it gets out,
就算传出去
people will only know
大家知道的也只是路卿卿
that Lu Qingqing uses all kinds of methods to be Crown Princess.
为了做太子妃不择手段
Mr. Lu is really the person who can do great things.
路大人不愧是做大事之人
Even the daughter you've raised for dozens of years,
即便是养了十几年的女儿
you show no mercy to her.
也毫不留情
But Lu Qingqing is still receiving her punishment in Manghuang forest.
只是路卿卿还在莽荒森林受罚
It isn't up to three months yet.
三月期限未到
We don't have much reason to let her come back.
我们没有足够的理由让她回来
Your Majesty,
王后
look at this.
您看这是什么
I didn't expect
没想到
she really gathered three treasures.
她还真的集齐了这三样宝物
But she
但是她自己呢
insisted on staying in Manghuang forest
执意要留在莽荒森林
to acknowledge Master Rongyun as her master
拜容云大师为师
and practice her magic power.
修炼灵力
But today I found the fusang fruit
可是今天老臣发现这扶桑果
actually came from a stone.
其实是石头所变
You mean
你的意思是
we can take advantage of it
我们可以借此
to call Lu Qingqing back.
把路卿卿召唤回来
Right.
不错
But I need Your Majesty's cooperation.
但是老臣需要王后的配合
General Lu Hongzhu's daughter Lu Qingqing
将军路鸿竹之女路卿卿
was sent to Manghuang forest because she made mistakes.
因犯错被派往莽荒森林历练
But she remains impenitent
却不思悔改
and deceived the Empress.
欺君罔上
She used the false treasure to dodge the Empress.
以假宝物搪塞王后娘娘
Lu Hongzhu indulges his daughter.
路鸿竹更是放任其女
Their intentions are devious.
其心当诛
Today I received the Empress's order
今接王后娘娘圣谕
to catch Lu Qingqing
捉拿路卿卿
and strictly guard Lu Maison.
严加看管路府
Even a bird can't fly out of it.
就是连只鸟都不能飞出去
Yes.
是